<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-11-11T15:35:32+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/index.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Work Permit Rejection Reasons and Rejection Cancellation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/en/rejection-of-work-permit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work Permit Rejection Reasons and Rejection Cancellation" /><published>2024-08-16T13:15:00+03:00</published><updated>2024-08-16T13:15:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/en/rejection-of-work-permit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/en/rejection-of-work-permit"><![CDATA[<div id="Reasons for Work Permit Rejection" class="jumptarget">
    <h3>Reasons for Work Permit Rejection</h3>
    <div id="A Clause (Non-Compliance with International Labor Policy)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>A Clause (Non-Compliance with International Labor Policy)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b>
        </div>
        <p>
            According to Article 9(a) of the International Labor Law, applications that do not comply with international labor policy are rejected. International labor policy is fundamentally based on the following principles:<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Policies developed to prioritize domestic labor in meeting Turkey's labor needs, as well as maintaining the sustainability of national employment policies, while ensuring a balance between local and foreign labor and benefiting from qualified foreign labor.<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Attracting highly qualified foreign labor who stand out in education level, professional experience, contributions to science and technology, and strategic importance in specific fields.<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Attracting highly qualified foreign investors to Turkey based on the size of investment, contribution to employment and economy, employment level, export volume, contribution to the region, province, or sector, and other similar factors.<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Implementation of international labor policy domestically and internationally through projects, plans, programs, and similar activities carried out by the General Directorate, and coordination with relevant institutions and organizations when necessary.<br />
            International labor policy is determined according to the above principles. In this sense, a work permit application that is found to be in violation of these principles will be rejected.
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="B Clause (Submission with False or Misleading Information and Documents)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>B Clause (Submission with False or Misleading Information and Documents)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b>
        </div>
        <p>
            According to Article 9(b) of the International Labor Law, applications made with false or misleading information and documents are rejected.
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="C Clause (Insufficient Justification for Employment of Foreigners)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>C Clause (Insufficient Justification for Employment of Foreigners)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b>
        </div>
        <p>
            According to Article 9(c) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the justification for employing the foreigner is insufficient. In this context, it is important to ensure that a detailed justification is provided for why the foreigner is preferred for employment, including their expertise and reasons for their hiring.
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="Ç Clause (Applications for Jobs and Professions Reserved for Turkish Citizens in Other Laws)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Ç Clause (Applications for Jobs and Professions Reserved for Turkish Citizens in Other Laws)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b>
        </div>
        <p>
            According to Article 9(ç) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications for jobs and professions reserved exclusively for Turkish citizens under other legal provisions are rejected. Jobs and professions reserved solely for Turkish citizens include:<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Founders, managers, and authorized representatives of private security companies<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Private security officers<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Neighborhood and district watchmen<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Financial advisory<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Board members of cooperatives<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Customs advisor assistants<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Founders of schools teaching in languages other than Turkish and those established by foreigners<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Responsible managers in private hospitals<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Dentistry<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Patient care<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Pharmacy<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Veterinary medicine<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Foreign assistant doctors outside specialty training<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Notaries<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Judges and prosecutors<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Human resources management<br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="D Clause (Foreigners Who Are Found Not to Have Required Qualifications and Expertise)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>D Clause (Foreigners Who Are Found Not to Have Required Qualifications and Expertise)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b>
        </div>
        <p>
            According to Article 9(d) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if it is determined that the foreigner does not possess the necessary qualifications and expertise. When determining the required qualifications and expertise:<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The foreigner's suitability for the job position applied for,<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Whether the job to be performed at the workplace requires expertise,<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>Professional experience and educational background,<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The validity of certificates and documents,<br />
                <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The foreigner's alignment with sectoral needs and requirements.<br />
            Foreigners who do not possess the required qualifications or whose expertise cannot be substantiated with documentation will have their work permits rejected.
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="E Clause (Not Meeting the Evaluation Criteria Set by the Ministry)" class="jumptarget">
    <h4>Clause E (Not Meeting the Evaluation Criteria Set by the Ministry)</h4>
    <div class="contact-person">
        <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b><p></p>
    </div>
    <p>
    According to Article 9(e) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if they do not meet the evaluation criteria set by the Ministry. Both the foreign applicant and the employer who will employ the foreigner must meet these criteria. The Ministry’s evaluation criteria for employers and foreigners are as follows:<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>At least 5 Turkish citizens must be employed at the workplace where the work permit is requested. If the foreigner requesting the permit is a company partner, the requirement for five employees is applied only to the last 6 months of a one-year work permit granted by the Ministry. In cases where multiple foreign work permit requests are made at the same workplace, each foreigner after the first one granted a work permit must have 5 Turkish citizens employed separately.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The workplace must have a paid-in capital of at least 100,000 TL or gross sales of at least 800,000 TL or an export amount of at least 250,000 USD in the last year.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>For foreigners working in associations and foundations, the criteria of Article 2 will apply. For foreigners working in foreign airline representations in Turkey, the education sector, and domestic services, Articles 1 and 2 will not apply.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The foreign company partner requesting the permit must have a capital share of at least 20% and not less than 40,000 TL.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>The declared monthly salary for the foreigner must be at a level commensurate with the foreigner's duties and qualifications. Accordingly, considering the minimum wage applicable at the time of application, the salary to be paid to the foreigner must be at least:
    </p>
    <div class="ml-3 mt-1 mb-1">
        <o><b>-</b></o>6.5 times the minimum wage for top executives and pilots<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>4 times the minimum wage for unit or branch managers, engineers, and architects<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>3 times the minimum wage for jobs requiring specialization and expertise, and for teachers<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>The minimum wage for foreigners working in domestic services, and 1.5 times the minimum wage for foreigners working in other professions<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>2 times the minimum wage for foreigners working in tourism-animation organization companies, including acrobats and similar roles, and for jobs like masseurs, masseuses, and SPA therapists<br />
        </div>
    <p>
    For entities:
    <div class="ml-3 mt-1 mb-1">
        <o><b>-</b></o>Tourism businesses with at least three stars certified by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, certified holiday villages, and thermal hotels with activity permits from official authorities<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Certified tourism establishments with a hamam-sauna-SPA complex, in agreement (contracted) facilities<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Officially authorized sports centers employing at least 20 Turkish citizens<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Requests to employ foreigners in jobs requiring specialization and expertise such as masseurs, masseuses, and SPA therapists will be considered, while requests from establishments not meeting these criteria will be deemed inappropriate.<br />
    </div>
    </p>
    <p>
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>For foreigners employed in the entertainment sector and in tourism-animation organization companies in jobs requiring specialization and expertise, the quota for employing 5 Turkish citizens separately for each foreigner will not apply if at least 10 Turkish citizens are employed.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>For foreigners to be employed in cases specified in bilateral or multilateral agreements to which Turkey is a party, and for foreigners employed in public institution and organization procurement or service contracts, the criteria in Articles 1 and 2 will not apply.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>For jobs requiring advanced technology or in cases where there are no Turkish experts with the same qualifications, the criteria in Articles 1 and 2 will not apply upon approval from the General Directorate.<br />
    <o class="fas fa-caret-right"></o>For foreigners to be employed in enterprises meeting the conditions of Special Direct Foreign Investment, excluding key personnel, the criteria set in Article 1 will be applied based on the number of Turkish citizens employed across all workplaces of the enterprise in the country.<br />
    Persons not meeting the above evaluation criteria will have their work permit applications rejected. However, there are some foreigners who are exempt from these criteria. These foreigners are required to obtain work permits. Exempt foreigners include:
    </p>
    <div class="ml-3 mt-1 mb-1">
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners with a Turkish citizen parent, spouse, or child<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners who have been married to a Turkish citizen for at least 3 years<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Citizens of the Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners granted residence permits under Turkish or related community practices<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners granted humanitarian residence permits<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners granted residence permits as victims of human trafficking<br />
        <o><b>-</b></o>Foreigners granted residence permits as stateless individuals<br />
    </div>
    <p>
    The above-mentioned foreigners will not have their work permit applications rejected if they apply, and they will be exempt from the evaluation criteria. However, they must prove their status with official documents.
    </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="Clause F (Regarding Foreigners Who Are Not Allowed to Enter Turkey, Not Granted Visas, or Are Reported by the Ministry of Interior as Subject to Deportation)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Clause F (Regarding Foreigners Who Are Not Allowed to Enter Turkey, Not Granted Visas, or Are Reported by the Ministry of Interior as Subject to Deportation)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        According to Article 9(f) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications must be rejected if they concern foreigners who are not allowed to enter Turkey, are not granted visas, or are reported by the Ministry of Interior as subject to deportation.<br />
        <br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="Clause G (Regarding Foreigners Whose Employment in Turkey is Considered Problematic from the Standpoint of Public Order, Public Security, or Public Health)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Clause G (Regarding Foreigners Whose Employment in Turkey is Considered Problematic from the Standpoint of Public Order, Public Security, or Public Health)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        According to Article 9(g) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the employment of foreigners is considered problematic from the standpoint of national security, public order, public security, or public health. For example, if a foreigner applying for a work permit has a contagious disease that would pose a risk to public health in Turkey, the work permit application should be rejected.<br />
        <br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="Clause Ğ (Applications Made by Citizens of Countries Recognized or with Diplomatic Relations with Turkey, Unless the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Gives a Favorable Opinion)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Clause Ğ (Applications Made by Citizens of Countries Recognized or with Diplomatic Relations with Turkey, Unless the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Gives a Favorable Opinion)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>According to Article 9(ğ) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications made by citizens of countries that are not recognized by Turkey or with which Turkey does not have diplomatic relations are rejected. Exceptionally, if the Ministry of Foreign Affairs provides a favorable opinion, the work permit application of the person may be accepted.<br />
        <br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="Clause H (Applications Not Made Within the Legal Period or Incomplete Applications)" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Clause H (Applications Not Made Within the Legal Period or Incomplete Applications)</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        According to Article 9(h) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the foreigner submits incomplete information and documents or fails to provide additional documents requested by the administration within the specified time. According to Article 19 of the International Labor Law, if there are missing information or documents in the application, the evaluation of the application is postponed. Subsequently, the applicant is requested to provide the missing documents through the system and electronic notification address.<br />
        <br />
        </p>
    </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Anıl Uzun</name></author><category term="Articles" /><category term="Information" /><category term="Work" /><category term="Permit" /><category term="Rejection Cancellation" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons for Work Permit Rejection A Clause (Non-Compliance with International Labor Policy) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(a) of the International Labor Law, applications that do not comply with international labor policy are rejected. International labor policy is fundamentally based on the following principles: Policies developed to prioritize domestic labor in meeting Turkey's labor needs, as well as maintaining the sustainability of national employment policies, while ensuring a balance between local and foreign labor and benefiting from qualified foreign labor. Attracting highly qualified foreign labor who stand out in education level, professional experience, contributions to science and technology, and strategic importance in specific fields. Attracting highly qualified foreign investors to Turkey based on the size of investment, contribution to employment and economy, employment level, export volume, contribution to the region, province, or sector, and other similar factors. Implementation of international labor policy domestically and internationally through projects, plans, programs, and similar activities carried out by the General Directorate, and coordination with relevant institutions and organizations when necessary. International labor policy is determined according to the above principles. In this sense, a work permit application that is found to be in violation of these principles will be rejected. B Clause (Submission with False or Misleading Information and Documents) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(b) of the International Labor Law, applications made with false or misleading information and documents are rejected. C Clause (Insufficient Justification for Employment of Foreigners) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(c) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the justification for employing the foreigner is insufficient. In this context, it is important to ensure that a detailed justification is provided for why the foreigner is preferred for employment, including their expertise and reasons for their hiring. Ç Clause (Applications for Jobs and Professions Reserved for Turkish Citizens in Other Laws) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(ç) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications for jobs and professions reserved exclusively for Turkish citizens under other legal provisions are rejected. Jobs and professions reserved solely for Turkish citizens include: Founders, managers, and authorized representatives of private security companies Private security officers Neighborhood and district watchmen Financial advisory Board members of cooperatives Customs advisor assistants Founders of schools teaching in languages other than Turkish and those established by foreigners Responsible managers in private hospitals Dentistry Patient care Pharmacy Veterinary medicine Foreign assistant doctors outside specialty training Notaries Judges and prosecutors Human resources management D Clause (Foreigners Who Are Found Not to Have Required Qualifications and Expertise) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(d) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if it is determined that the foreigner does not possess the necessary qualifications and expertise. When determining the required qualifications and expertise: The foreigner's suitability for the job position applied for, Whether the job to be performed at the workplace requires expertise, Professional experience and educational background, The validity of certificates and documents, The foreigner's alignment with sectoral needs and requirements. Foreigners who do not possess the required qualifications or whose expertise cannot be substantiated with documentation will have their work permits rejected. Clause E (Not Meeting the Evaluation Criteria Set by the Ministry) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(e) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if they do not meet the evaluation criteria set by the Ministry. Both the foreign applicant and the employer who will employ the foreigner must meet these criteria. The Ministry’s evaluation criteria for employers and foreigners are as follows: At least 5 Turkish citizens must be employed at the workplace where the work permit is requested. If the foreigner requesting the permit is a company partner, the requirement for five employees is applied only to the last 6 months of a one-year work permit granted by the Ministry. In cases where multiple foreign work permit requests are made at the same workplace, each foreigner after the first one granted a work permit must have 5 Turkish citizens employed separately. The workplace must have a paid-in capital of at least 100,000 TL or gross sales of at least 800,000 TL or an export amount of at least 250,000 USD in the last year. For foreigners working in associations and foundations, the criteria of Article 2 will apply. For foreigners working in foreign airline representations in Turkey, the education sector, and domestic services, Articles 1 and 2 will not apply. The foreign company partner requesting the permit must have a capital share of at least 20% and not less than 40,000 TL. The declared monthly salary for the foreigner must be at a level commensurate with the foreigner's duties and qualifications. Accordingly, considering the minimum wage applicable at the time of application, the salary to be paid to the foreigner must be at least: -6.5 times the minimum wage for top executives and pilots -4 times the minimum wage for unit or branch managers, engineers, and architects -3 times the minimum wage for jobs requiring specialization and expertise, and for teachers -The minimum wage for foreigners working in domestic services, and 1.5 times the minimum wage for foreigners working in other professions -2 times the minimum wage for foreigners working in tourism-animation organization companies, including acrobats and similar roles, and for jobs like masseurs, masseuses, and SPA therapists For entities: -Tourism businesses with at least three stars certified by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, certified holiday villages, and thermal hotels with activity permits from official authorities -Certified tourism establishments with a hamam-sauna-SPA complex, in agreement (contracted) facilities -Officially authorized sports centers employing at least 20 Turkish citizens -Requests to employ foreigners in jobs requiring specialization and expertise such as masseurs, masseuses, and SPA therapists will be considered, while requests from establishments not meeting these criteria will be deemed inappropriate. For foreigners employed in the entertainment sector and in tourism-animation organization companies in jobs requiring specialization and expertise, the quota for employing 5 Turkish citizens separately for each foreigner will not apply if at least 10 Turkish citizens are employed. For foreigners to be employed in cases specified in bilateral or multilateral agreements to which Turkey is a party, and for foreigners employed in public institution and organization procurement or service contracts, the criteria in Articles 1 and 2 will not apply. For jobs requiring advanced technology or in cases where there are no Turkish experts with the same qualifications, the criteria in Articles 1 and 2 will not apply upon approval from the General Directorate. For foreigners to be employed in enterprises meeting the conditions of Special Direct Foreign Investment, excluding key personnel, the criteria set in Article 1 will be applied based on the number of Turkish citizens employed across all workplaces of the enterprise in the country. Persons not meeting the above evaluation criteria will have their work permit applications rejected. However, there are some foreigners who are exempt from these criteria. These foreigners are required to obtain work permits. Exempt foreigners include: -Foreigners with a Turkish citizen parent, spouse, or child -Foreigners who have been married to a Turkish citizen for at least 3 years -Citizens of the Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus -Foreigners granted residence permits under Turkish or related community practices -Foreigners granted humanitarian residence permits -Foreigners granted residence permits as victims of human trafficking -Foreigners granted residence permits as stateless individuals The above-mentioned foreigners will not have their work permit applications rejected if they apply, and they will be exempt from the evaluation criteria. However, they must prove their status with official documents. Clause F (Regarding Foreigners Who Are Not Allowed to Enter Turkey, Not Granted Visas, or Are Reported by the Ministry of Interior as Subject to Deportation) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(f) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications must be rejected if they concern foreigners who are not allowed to enter Turkey, are not granted visas, or are reported by the Ministry of Interior as subject to deportation. Clause G (Regarding Foreigners Whose Employment in Turkey is Considered Problematic from the Standpoint of Public Order, Public Security, or Public Health) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(g) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the employment of foreigners is considered problematic from the standpoint of national security, public order, public security, or public health. For example, if a foreigner applying for a work permit has a contagious disease that would pose a risk to public health in Turkey, the work permit application should be rejected. Clause Ğ (Applications Made by Citizens of Countries Recognized or with Diplomatic Relations with Turkey, Unless the Ministry of Foreign Affairs Gives a Favorable Opinion) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(ğ) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications made by citizens of countries that are not recognized by Turkey or with which Turkey does not have diplomatic relations are rejected. Exceptionally, if the Ministry of Foreign Affairs provides a favorable opinion, the work permit application of the person may be accepted. Clause H (Applications Not Made Within the Legal Period or Incomplete Applications) Click Here to Contact Us to Cancel Your Work Permit Rejection According to Article 9(h) of the International Labor Law, work permit applications are rejected if the foreigner submits incomplete information and documents or fails to provide additional documents requested by the administration within the specified time. According to Article 19 of the International Labor Law, if there are missing information or documents in the application, the evaluation of the application is postponed. Subsequently, the applicant is requested to provide the missing documents through the system and electronic notification address.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Restriction Codes and Removal of Restriction Codes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/en/what-are-restriction-codes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Restriction Codes and Removal of Restriction Codes" /><published>2023-09-05T10:20:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-09-05T10:20:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/en/what-are-restriction-codes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/en/what-are-restriction-codes"><![CDATA[<div id="What is a Restriction Code?" class="jumptarget">
    <h3>What is a Restriction Code?</h3>
    <p>The restriction code is an informative code added to the records of foreigners in our country. Restriction codes can sometimes be added for informational purposes only, sometimes to impose a ban on entry into our country, and in some cases to deport the foreigner.</p>
</div>

<div id="Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
    <h3>Restriction Codes</h3>
    <div id="Ç Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>Ç Restriction Codes</h4>
            <div class="contact-person">
                <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click to get help in removing the Restriction Code added to your record and contact us</span></a></b><p></p>
            </div>
        <blockquote class="blockquote single-quote grey-bg link-box">
            <li><h5><p>
                <a href="#Ç-101">Ç-101</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-102">Ç-102</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-103">Ç-103</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-104">Ç-104</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-105">Ç-105</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-113">Ç-113</a>
                <a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-114">Ç-114</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-115">Ç-115</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-116">Ç-116</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-117">Ç-117</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-118">Ç-118</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-119">Ç-119</a>
                <a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-120">Ç-120</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-135">Ç-135</a><br /><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-136">Ç-136</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-137">Ç-137</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-138">Ç-138</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-141">Ç-141</a>
                <a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-150">Ç-150</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-151">Ç-151</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-152">Ç-152</a><a class="ml-2" href="#Ç-166">Ç-166</a>
            </p></h5></li>
        </blockquote>
        <p>
        <o id="Ç-101" class="jumptarget">1 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-101</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when any condition of the residence permit, work permit, visa, or visa exemption is violated. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 3-Month Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Can be removed along with the entry ban to Turkey through a visa with annotation or legal action.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-102" class="jumptarget">2 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-102</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when any condition of the residence permit, work permit, visa, or visa exemption is violated. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 6-Month Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Can be removed along with the entry ban to Turkey through a visa with annotation or legal action.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-103" class="jumptarget">3 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-103</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when any condition of the residence permit, work permit, visa, or visa exemption is violated. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 1-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Can be removed along with the entry ban to Turkey through a visa with annotation or legal action.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-104" class="jumptarget">4 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-104</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when any condition of the residence permit, work permit, visa, or visa exemption is violated. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Can be removed along with the entry ban to Turkey through a visa with annotation or legal action.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-105" class="jumptarget">5 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-105</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when any condition of the residence permit, work permit, visa, or visa exemption is violated. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 3-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Can be removed along with the entry ban to Turkey through a visa with annotation or legal action.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-113" class="jumptarget">6 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-113</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when illegal entry-exit to Turkey occurs. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-114" class="jumptarget">7 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-114</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners who have been subjected to judicial proceedings. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /><br />
        <o id="Ç-115" class="jumptarget">8 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-115</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners released from prison. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 1-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-116" class="jumptarget">9 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-116</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners who pose a threat to public morals and public health. <br /> 
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 1-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-117" class="jumptarget">10 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-117</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 1-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-118" class="jumptarget">11 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-118</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br /> 
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br /> 
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-119" class="jumptarget">12 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-119</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 3-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-120" class="jumptarget">13 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-120</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners who do not comply with the deportation decision. <br /> 
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 5-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-135" class="jumptarget">14 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-135</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed when the foreigner’s identity cannot be verified. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - Fine <br /> 
        - 5-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-136" class="jumptarget">15 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-136</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners expelled from Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-137" class="jumptarget">16 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-137</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners deported from Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 3-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-138" class="jumptarget">17 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-138</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners deported from Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 5-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-141" class="jumptarget">18 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-141</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners found to be conducting business, working, or residing illegally. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 5-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-150" class="jumptarget">19 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-150</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-151" class="jumptarget">20 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-151</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 3-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-152" class="jumptarget">21 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-152</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 5-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        <br />
        <o id="Ç-166" class="jumptarget">22 )</o> <bl><b>Ç-166</b></bl> This restriction code is imposed on foreigners working illegally in Turkey. <br />
        <b>Consequences :</b> <br /> 
        - 2-Year Ban on Entry to Turkey <br />
        Entry to Turkey can be reinstated through a visa with annotation. <br />
        </p>
        <br />
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="V Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
    <h4>V Restriction Codes</h4>
    <div class="contact-person">
        <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click here for assistance in removing the restriction code added to your registration and to contact us</span></a></b><p></p>
    </div>
    <blockquote class="blockquote single-quote grey-bg link-box">
        <li><h5><p>
            <a href="#V-68">V-68</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-69">V-69</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-70">V-70</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-71">V-71</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-74">V-74</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-84">V-84</a>
            <a class="ml-2" href="#V-87">V-87</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-88">V-88</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-91">V-91</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-92">V-92</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-137">V-137</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-144">V-144</a>
            <a class="ml-2" href="#V-146">V-146</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-147">V-147</a><br /><a class="ml-2" href="#V-148">V-148</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-154">V-154</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-157">V-157</a><a class="ml-2" href="#V-158">V-158</a>
            <a class="ml-2" href="#V-159">V-159</a>
        </p></h5></li>
    </blockquote>
    <p>
    <o id="V-68" class="jumptarget">1 )</o> <bl><b>V-68</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who need to obtain permission from the ministry to obtain a residence permit.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-69" class="jumptarget">2 )</o> <bl><b>V-69</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners whose residence permit has been canceled due to failure to meet the conditions required for the residence permit.<br />
    <b>Consequences:</b><br />
    - If you do not exit Turkey within 3 months after your residence permit is canceled, an entry ban may be applied and different restriction codes may emerge.<br />
    It can be resolved by obtaining a new residence permit.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-70" class="jumptarget">3 )</o> <bl><b>V-70</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who were found to have engaged in fake marriages to obtain a residence permit in Turkey.<br />
    <b>Consequences:</b> <br />
    - 5 Years Entry Ban to Turkey<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-71" class="jumptarget">4 )</o> <bl><b>V-71</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who cannot be found at the address they stated when applying for a residence permit.<br />
    It can be resolved through an administrative application.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-74" class="jumptarget">5 )</o> <bl><b>V-74</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who must notify the ministry or governorships before leaving the country.<br />
    It can be resolved through an administrative application or lawsuit.<br />
    <br />
    <o>6 )</o> <bl><b>V-77</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who are not Ahıska Turks but applied as Ahıska Turks, preventing them from making another Ahıska Turk application.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-84" class="jumptarget">7 )</o> <bl><b>V-84</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who enter Turkey and do not apply for a residence permit within the given period, based on the condition of obtaining a residence permit within 10 days.<br />
    <b>Consequences:</b>
    <p>- First 3 months of not exiting:</p>
        <div class="pl-4 mt-1 mb-1">
        <p>) 3 Months Entry Ban to Turkey</p>
        </div>
    <p>- First 3-6 months of not exiting:</p>
        <div class="pl-4 mt-1 mb-1">
        <p>) 6 Months Entry Ban to Turkey</p>
        </div>
    <p>- First 6 months - 1 year of not exiting:</p>
        <div class="pl-4 mt-1 mb-1">
        <p>) 1 Year Entry Ban to Turkey</p>
        </div>
    <p>If no exit from Turkey is made, this period can extend up to 5 years.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-87" class="jumptarget">8 )</o> <bl><b>V-87</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who were under temporary protection in Turkey and voluntarily returned to their country.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-88" class="jumptarget">9 )</o> <bl><b>V-88</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners whose work permit has been canceled.<br />
    It should be resolved through a new work permit application, a documented invitation, or administrative lawsuit.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-91" class="jumptarget">10 )</o> <bl><b>V-91</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who are under temporary protection in Turkey and must obtain permission to leave Turkey.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-92" class="jumptarget">11 )</o> <bl><b>V-92</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners under temporary protection with double registration.<br />
    If it does not self-correct, an administrative application is required to correct it.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-137" class="jumptarget">12 )</o> <bl><b>V-137</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who were invited to leave Turkey and did not leave Turkey within the specified period of -15 days-.<br />
    <b>Consequences:</b><br />
    - Deportation decision<br />
    - 5 Years Entry Ban to Turkey<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-144" class="jumptarget">13 )</o> <bl><b>V-144</b></bl> If deportation decisions have been made for foreigners who cannot return to their country for various reasons or who would face a serious danger if they return, and deporting them to a third country is not deemed appropriate, the deportation decision is not implemented. In this case, a humanitarian residence permit is granted and the V-144 code is applied.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-146" class="jumptarget">14 )</o> <bl><b>V-146</b></bl> Some Turkish citizens who have judicial actions initiated against them with the V-146 code may have annotations applied to their passports in practice. In some cases, the passport applications of these individuals may not be finalized.<br />
    Since this situation constitutes a violation of law, a lawsuit should be filed following an administrative application.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-147" class="jumptarget">15 )</o> <bl><b>V-147</b></bl> Sometimes, the V-147 code may also be annotated on the passports of the spouses of those with the V-146 code.<br />
    Since this situation constitutes a greater violation of law, a lawsuit should be filed following an administrative application.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-148" class="jumptarget">16 )</o> <bl><b>V-148</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners staying in temporary accommodation centers for informational purposes.<br />
    It can be removed through an administrative application once the accommodation process in the center is completed.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-154" class="jumptarget">17 )</o> <bl><b>V-154</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to individuals who apply to the administrative court against a deportation decision.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-157" class="jumptarget">18 )</o> <bl><b>V-157</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners whose residence permit requests have been rejected.<br />
    It can be removed through a documented visa or by filing a lawsuit against the decision to reject the residence permit application in the administrative court.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-158" class="jumptarget">19 )</o> <bl><b>V-158</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied when the identity cards of foreign diplomatic staff or family members are canceled.<br />
    It can be resolved through an administrative application or lawsuit.<br />
    <br />
    <o id="V-159" class="jumptarget">20 )</o> <bl><b>V-159</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners coming to our country for transit to a third country.<br />
    It is only for informational purposes and does not have any harmful effects.<br />
    <br />
    </p>
    </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="G Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>G Restriction Codes</h4>
        <blockquote class="blockquote single-quote grey-bg link-box">
            <li><h5><p>
                <a href="#G-26">G-26</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-34">G-34</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-42">G-42</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-43">G-43</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-48">G-48</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-58">G-58</a>
                <a class="ml-2" href="#G-64">G-64</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-65">G-65</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-67">G-67</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-78">G-78</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-82">G-82</a><a class="ml-2" href="#G-87">G-87</a>
            </p></h5></li>
        </blockquote>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click here for assistance in removing the restriction code added to your registration and to contact us</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        <o id="G-26" class="jumptarget">1 )</o> <bl><b>G-26</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners suspected of involvement in or known to be engaged in illegal organization activities.<br />
        It can be removed through legal proceedings.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-34" class="jumptarget">2 )</o> <bl><b>G-34</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected to have committed forgery.<br />
        It can be removed through legal proceedings.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-42" class="jumptarget">3 )</o> <bl><b>G-42</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing drug offenses.<br />
        It can be removed through legal proceedings.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-43" class="jumptarget">4 )</o> <bl><b>G-43</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing smuggling offenses.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-48" class="jumptarget">5 )</o> <bl><b>G-48</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of facilitating or providing premises for prostitution.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-58" class="jumptarget">6 )</o> <bl><b>G-58</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing murder offenses.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-64" class="jumptarget">7 )</o> <bl><b>G-64</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing threats.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-65" class="jumptarget">8 )</o> <bl><b>G-65</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing theft.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-66" class="jumptarget">9 )</o> <bl><b>G-66</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing robbery.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-67" class="jumptarget">10 )</o> <bl><b>G-67</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners known or suspected of committing fraud.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-78" class="jumptarget">11 )</o> <bl><b>G-78</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners identified as carriers of infectious diseases.<br />
        <b>Consequences:</b><br />
        - Indefinite entry ban to Turkey<br />
        If the diagnosis is found to be erroneous or the disease is treated and eliminated, the entry ban can be lifted by application.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-82" class="jumptarget">12 )</o> <bl><b>G-82</b></bl> Activities against national security.<br />
        <br />
        <o id="G-87" class="jumptarget">13 )</o> <bl><b>G-87</b></bl> Individuals considered a threat to general security.<br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="N Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>N Restriction Codes</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click here for assistance in removing the restriction code added to your registration and to contact us</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        <o>1 )</o> <bl><b>N-82</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who need prior permission to enter Turkey. Since this permission is generally not granted, the restriction code usually needs to be removed for entry into Turkey.<br />
        <br />
        <o>2 )</o> <bl><b>N-99</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners with an Interpol alert.<br />
        <b>Consequences:</b> <br />
        - An entry ban to Turkey may be imposed depending on the state's decision.<br />
        It can be lifted.<br />
        <br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="K Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>K Restriction Codes</h4>
        <p>
        <o>1 )</o> <bl><b>K</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who have arrest warrants issued for smuggling. It aims to prevent their departure from Turkey.<br />
        </p>
    </div>
    <div class="row">
        <div class="col-xl-12 text-center pb-40 ">
            <div class="section-title service-title">
                <img src="/en/assets/img/pin.png" class="img-fluid" alt="" />
            </div>
        </div>
    </div>
    <div id="O Restriction Codes" class="jumptarget">
        <h4>O Restriction Codes</h4>
        <div class="contact-person">
            <b><a href="/sayfalar/iletisim"><span><i class="fas fa-phone"></i>Click here for assistance in removing the restriction code added to your registration and to contact us</span></a></b><p></p>
        </div>
        <p>
        <o>1 )</o> <bl><b>O-100</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners who were found not to be residing at the address they declared when applying as asylum seekers.<br />
        <br />
        <o>2 )</o> <bl><b>O-176</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners whose international protection application was negatively assessed.<br />
        <b>Consequences:</b> <br />
        - 3 Years Entry Ban to Turkey<br />
        <br />
        <o>3 )</o> <bl><b>O-177</b></bl> This is a restriction code applied to foreigners whose international protection application was negatively assessed.<br />
        <b>Consequences:</b> <br />
        - 5 Years Entry Ban to Turkey<br />
        </p>
    </div>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Anıl Uzun</name></author><category term="Articles" /><category term="Information" /><category term="Restriction" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is a Restriction Code? The restriction code is an informative code added to the records of foreigners in our country. Restriction codes can sometimes be added for informational purposes only, sometimes to impose a ban on entry into our country, and in some cases to deport the foreigner.]]></summary></entry></feed>